{
    "id": "637dc14995e84972abce82041719cfcd",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I have been in such a pickle …………………….. I saw you last.",
            "description": "Since can indicate time. It is used to show the starting point of something.",
            "answers": [
                "since",
                "after",
                "when"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………… him since that unfortunate incident.",
            "description": "When since indicates time, it is preceded by a verb in the present perfect tense.",
            "answers": [
                "did not see",
                "have not seen",
                "don't see"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The soldiers were not wanting in strength or courage ……………………… they were badly fed.",
            "description": "But is used to connect two contradictory ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "but",
                "since"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked him ……………………… he would help me.",
            "description": "We use if to introduce indirect questions.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "if",
                "unless"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He was annoyed …………………………….. he was contradicted.",
            "description": "We can use that to express a reason or cause. It is equivalent to because.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "because",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He kept quiet …………………………… the situation wouldn’t get worse.",
            "description": "That can indicate purpose. It is equivalent to in order that.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "for",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He bled so profusely ……………………….. he died.",
            "description": "That can express a consequence or result.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "because",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I see you oftener …………………………. I see him.",
            "description": "Than is a conjunction and it follows adjectives or adverbs in the comparative degree. ",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "then",
                "as"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. there is life, there is hope.",
            "description": "While can mean during the time that. It is similar to as long as.",
            "answers": [
                "While",
                "As long as",
                "Whereas"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………….. this is true of some, it is not true of all.",
            "description": "While can mean whereas.",
            "answers": [
                "While",
                "Whereas",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He abhorred hypocrisy …………………………. he was not too stern with the hypocrite.",
            "description": "We use but to connect two contradictory ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "as",
                "and",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. he lived he was the guiding star of a brave nation.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "As long as",
                "Whereas",
                "Since"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}